DIEGO GARCÍA LOZANO

DATA SCIENTIST

CONTACT

+34 665215332

diegoglozano96@gmail.com

https://diegoglozano.netlify.app/

Madrid, Spain

SKILLS

Python/SQL/R

Pandas/Polars/Spark/sklearn/xgboost/ streamlit

Databricks/Linux

Communication and team work

EDUCATION

BSc Telecommunications engineering

Universidad de Oviedo

2014 - 2019

Mention in telematics

MSc Mathematical and computational engineering

UOC

2021 - Unfinished

Proffesional musician - Flute

Conservatorio de Oviedo

2009 - 2016

LANGUAGES

English - C1 by Cambridge

Native spanish

PROFILE

Telecommunications engineer and Data Scientist with +4 years of experience. I have strong Python and SQL skills, and I have worked in many different projects and industries

I have technical skills that cover many aspects, from machine learning, statistics, NLP, data visualisation or models deployment to data engineering or arquitecture. Strong foundation in mathematics and very interested in other fields, like economy, business, experimentation or causal inference. Willingness to learn, grow, and achieve new goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

HP Inc 2022 - Now

- Working in a global team that recommends best prices for almost all B2B HP deals in the world, earning ~10M\$ per year. Responsible for Europe models and UK&I deployment
- Develop solutions for model monitoring (concept and data drift)
- Improvement of processes: migrating a local ETL to Databricks and rewriting to Spark with a decrease of ~90% of time
- Applying best practices in the team: implement the correct git flow and automation of processes
- Deployment of different apps in Linux machines to increase the adoption of our models among the stakeholders
- Communication with other teams, like data engineers, MLOps, business teams...

Data Scientist

Endesa 2020-2022

- Working in the Advanced Analytics team, which is responsible for all data projects of the company
- Worked for many business teams, like B2B, B2C or demand and prices
- B2B: credit risk and recommending best product for potential clients
- B2C: sales
- Demand and prices: stock simulation with Monte Carlo Markov chains

Data Scientist

Santander Bank 2019-2020

- Non-financial risks: NLP for reputational risk
- Santander technology: data engineering and arquitecture

Data Scientist

University of Oviedo

2019

 Development of a classifier for income calls to the number 060 with NLP techniques, saving much money in the contact center



